Okay. Let's
假设 Audacity 进行实验
suppose Audacity runs an experiment where they test changing the color and
以测试
placement of the Start Now button.
“现在开始”按钮颜色和位置的更改效果
Their metric is click-through-rate and they divert by cookie.
他们选择的指标是点击率 分组单元为 cookie
Their practical significance boundary is .01 and they use an alpha of .05 and
实际显著性最小值为 0.01 α 值为 0.05
a beta of 0.2.
β 值为 0.2
Now here are the results of the experiment which was run over
实验运行一周后的结果
seven days.
如下
And the total numbers are on the last row.
最后一行为总数
I won't go over it now, but if you do a sanity check, you'll find that
现在先不看实验结果 但是如果进行完整性检查
the number of page views is comparable between the two groups.
你就会发现 两组的页面浏览量具有可比性
So let's start analyzing.
现在开始分析实验结果
Now, in lesson one, we analyzed a similar experiment, but
在第一课里 我们分析了一项类似的实验
we measured click-through probability instead of click-through rate, so
但我们测量的是点击概率而非点击率
we could assume a binomial distribution.
可以做出二项分布假设
With click-through rate, like I mentioned in lesson four,
就像我在第四课里提到的
the distribution is more likely to be Poisson,
点击率很可能形成泊松分布假设
which is harder to deal with analytically than the binomial.
其分析比二项分布更加困难
So this time, in order to calculate a confidence interval,
所以此次 为计算置信区间
it's a good idea to estimate the variance empirically.
通过实证估算方差是个好主意
In fact, Audacity already calculated the empirical standard error when they
事实上 早在进行实验规模决策时
decided what size to use for their experiment.
Audacity 就已经计算出了实证标准误差
With a sample size of 10,000 page views in each group,
当每组页面浏览量的样本量为 10,000 时
they had measured the standard error to be 0.0035.
算得标准误差为 0.0035
As in lesson four, I can assume that the standard error is proportional to
根据第四课的知识 可以假设标准误差
one over the square root of N.
与 N 的平方根之一成正比
However, N here was the sample size of one group, which works well if there's
但是 这里的 N 是一组的样本量
the same size in both groups, as in the estimation of the standard error.
如果两组数据的样本量相同 则可通过这种比例关系直接估算标准误差
But in our results, there's not the same number of page views in both groups.
但是在我们的实验结果中 两组数据的样本量并不相同
In this case, I can assume that the standard error is proportional
在此情况下 可以
to the square root of 1 over N1 plus 1 over n2,
假设标准误差与两者之和的平方根之一成正比
and this did work well if the ends are fairly close.
如果 N1 和 N2 尾数相近时 计算很简便
This should also look familiar.
这看起来很眼熟
It comes up in the formula for
它也出现在二项分布
pooled standard error in the binomial distribution.
合并标准误差的计算公式里
So then the standard error for our experiment can be determined using this
因此 计算本项实验的标准误差
equation, where the empirical standard error divided by the empirical scaling
可以使用以下等式
factor is equal to the standard error for our experiment,
即实证标准误差除以实证比例系数
divided by the scaling factor for our experiment, which involves the number of
等于本项实验的标准误差除以本项实验的比例系数
page views in both the control and the experiment group for our experiment.
其中本项实验的比例系数与对照组和实验组的页面浏览量相关
So then the standard error for our experiment comes out to 0.0041.
算得实验标准误差为 0.0041
Now we'll replace this table of results with just the total numbers,
接下来为了腾出空间
to make a little more room.
我们要用总数代替整个实验结果表格
Now I'll estimate the difference between the click-through rates and
现在要计算
the control and experiment groups by subtracting the control
对照组和实验组的点击率之差
estimated click-through rate from the experiment estimated click-through rate,
实验组点击率减去对照组点击率
and this comes out to 0.0300.
得出的结果为 0.0300
Then, the margin of error is the standard error times 1.96,
再计算误差范围
which comes to 0.0080.
标准误差乘以 1.96 等于 0.0080
Then, the confidence interval is from 0.0020 to 0.0380.
置信区间则为 0.0020 至 0.0380
Based on this, I would recommend launching the experiment.
根据以上数据 我会建议进行实验
The confidence interval does not include the practical significance boundary
置信区间不包括实际显著性最小值 0.01
of 0.01, meaning I can be confident at a 95% confidence level that
这说明 我有 95% 的把握可以判定
the true change is large enough to be worth launching.
更改网页成效明显 具有推行价值
However, just to double check, let's look at the results of the sign test.
但是 保险起见 我们可以通过符号检验复查一下
To do this, I'll need to bring up the day by day data again.
为此 还得用到每天的具体数据
Here, to the clicks columns, I've also added the click through rate, so
在表格的点击量一栏里 我又增加了点击率
that's just the clicks divided by the page views for each row.
也就是每行的点击量除以对应的页面浏览量
To do a sign test, I need to know the number of days, which in this case is
符号检验需要知道实验天数 本项实验运行的天数为 7
seven, and I also need to know the number of days with a positive change.
另外 还需要知道更改效果为正的实验天数
So comparing the click through rate in each row, I can see that the experiment
对比各行的点击率后发现
group actually had a higher click through rate on all seven days.
实验组每天的点击率都很高
This certainly looks good for
这从表面看来对实验有利
the experiment, but what will be the chance of this happening randomly?
但是这种情况随机发生的可能性有多大？
If there was no difference,
如果不考虑其他因素
then there would be a 50% chance of a positive change on each day.
网页更改每天都有一半机会取得积极成效
So the question is if you flip a fair coin seven times,
所以接下来的问题是 如果在相同条件下分别运行实验 7 次
what is the chance it comes up heads seven times?
得到积极成果的概率有多大？
This is the same calculation I did earlier to do a population count
它的计算方法与前面总体完整性检查
sanity check.
相同
Earlier, I used a binomial distribution where each event was a cookie, and
在之前的课程中 我采用了二项分布公式 将 cookie 定义为事件
the two outcomes were being assigned to the control group or
得到的两个结果
the experiment group.
分别分配给对照组和实验组
Here, the event is a day, and the two outcomes are a positive change or
本项实验中 事件为每天 得出的两个结果为积极成果和消极后果
a negative change, and the probability of each outcome is 50%.
且得出某一结果的概率为 50%
The main difference is that here,
两种计算方式的区别主要在于
we cannot assume a normal distribution, since seven days is not enough for
本项实验不可假设为二项分布 但是仅运行 7 天
the binomial to closely approximate a normal.
不足以提升为正态分布假设
You can do the calculation by hand using the probability density of the binomial
你可以根据二项分布的概率密度 笔算出结果
distribution, but there's also an online calculator that
不过你也可以借助在线计算器
you can use which is linked in the instructor's notes.
计算器链接参见讲师注释
I'll use the online calculator.
我将使用在线计算器进行计算
First, I'll need to enter the number of successes I observed.
首先 输入观察到的成功数量
I'll define a positive difference, or
我将“结果”定义为积极成果
the experiment group having a higher click-through-rate than the control
即实验组点击率高于对照组
as a success, so there were seven successes out of seven total days.
则实验运行 7 天 成功的结果数量为 7
Then I'll leave the probability at 0.5 and click Calculate Probabilities.
然后在概率处填入 0.5 点击“计算概率”
The number I'm interested in here is the two-tail P value, which is 0.0156.
我想得到的数据是双尾 P 值 结果为 0.0156
That's the probability of observing a result at least this extreme by chance.
即为随机得到积极成果的概率
Since this is less than the chosen alpha of 0.05, the sign test agrees with
由于该数据小于设定的 α 值 0.05 符号检验的结果与假设检验一致
the hypothesis test, that this result was unlikely to come about by chance.
表明积极成果的出现不具有随机性
Given this, my recommendation would not change.
因此 我的建议不会改变
I would definitely launch the experiment with increased confidence in
根据实验结果
the experiment results.
我对于实验的实际推行更有信心
Now, I want you to do the same analysis for this table of results.
现在我想请你们用同样的方法 对以下实验结果进行分析
Again, the metric for the experiment was click-through rate, and
实验指标仍为点击率
the practical significance boundary is 0.01, and the alpha is 0.05.
实际显著性最小值为 0.01 α 值为 0.05
These are the results for the first week of the experiment, and
左边是第一周的实验结果
these are the results for the second week.
右边是第二周的实验结果
I've put the click-through rate instead of the number of clicks in these columns
为降低分析难度
to make the analysis a little easier.
点击情况一列给出的不是点击量 而是点击率
You can also find these results in the spreadsheet linked in
这些实验数据也可以
the instructor's notes.
从讲师注释中的电子数据表里获得
Audacity also empirically estimated that the standard error for the click through
Audacity 已经计算出 当每组样本量的页面浏览量为 5,000 时
rate to be .0062 with a sample size of 5,000 page views in each group.
点击率的标准误差为 0.0062
Like I did, you should both do a sign test on the day by day data and
参照我的分析步骤 你应该对每天的数据进行符号检验
computer confidence interval of the effect size, that is, the difference
并计算出效应值的置信区间
between the click through rate in the control group and the experiment group.
即对照组与实验组的点击率之差
Click the lower and upper balance of your confidence interval in these boxes
点击方框 输入置信区间的最大值和最小值
and the the two tailed p value for
后面的方框输出符号检验的双尾 P 值
your sign test in this box, all to four decimal places.
以上数据精确到小数点后四位
For each test, are the results statistically significant that the alpha
当 α 值为 0.05 时
equals 0.05 level?
各项检验的结果是否具有统计显著性？
Finally, discuss on the forums what recommendation you would give
最后 得出实验的分析结果后
if you saw these results in an experiment you were running.
请到论坛里讨论你将给出的建议
Would you recommend to launch?
你会建议落实吗？
Not launch?
还是不落实？
Dig deeper into something strange looking?
你会深入研究异常数据吗？
Would it be a judgment call that depended on the business strategy?
实验的推行与否是取决于业务策略？
Once you've discussed your thoughts, check this box.
谈论过后请勾选此方框